# Ali Lazim

San Francisco, California, United States



ali.lazim@cr34.com



+905333102292



linkedin.com/in/ali-lazim-510b156

### **Summary**

Solid of more than 30 years of experiences in software engineering, project management and industry analysis. Broad range of experience and demonstrated ability;

- Successfully combines deep technical and business/customer understanding.
- Deep, quick thinker; pragmatic solutions to thorny problems on-demand.
- Highly credible RE/DE Personnel skills with experiences in National, EU and International RE/DE projects.
- Wide experiences in the whole stages of the Software development life cycle.
- Extensive skills and experience in the whole processes of PMI project Management, Scrum and Agile.
- Communicates effectively across varied audiences.
- Instinctive understanding of the Open Source/Linux community dynamic.
- Extensive skills and experiences in electric electronic and mechatronic projects.

Deep technical understanding of "scale", "infrastructure", "high availability", and "security" issues. Thorough grasp of the subtleties of the software development process; pragmatic and successful ability to apply that understanding.

Seeking a challenging position as a CTO / technical lead / project(s) manager to be part of a team and play a key role in meeting the overall team objectives and programme milestones.

Specialties: IT, Software Development, Security, Penetration test, Auditing, IAM, Identity Governance and Projects Management: PMI Project Management, SCRUM and Agile, Microsoft Project.

Software Engineering and Development: Main Experiences in Open Source Languages and Tools; - Java Technologies, API's and Frameworks (J2EE, J2SE, J2ME, Android), HTML5, Objective-C, Node.js, .Net, PHP.

Infrastructures/Technologies/Concepts: Cloud Computing, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS), Containers such as Kubernetes, BeyondCorp, P2P, GRID, Telecom & GSM infrastructure, Pattern Recognition, ANN, SOA, Web 2.0, RIA, JScript, Ajax, RSS, Web Push, VoIP Systems.

Hardware: Extensive skills and experiences in innovating, designing, developing, prototyping, managing and manufacturing; electric, electronic, mechanical and mechatronic products.

## **Experience**



### Chief Technology Officer

### **SAASPASS**

Jan 2012 - Present (10 years 2 months +)

I started with SAASPASS from the start with coming up with the idea and researching how visible it is. I managed the whole stages of this product/software development life cycle, DevOps, cloud/on-prem integrations and the live operations/maintenance.

In brief:

Windows, Mac OS X, Unix and Linux

System Architecture

On-prem integration and deployment

Cloud Computing, deployment and hosting (Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Amazon Web Services (AWS))

Containers such as Kubernetes

Virtualization and VDI technologies

Agile/Scrum and PMP Project management

Databases design and development (SQL)

Software Analysis, Architecture and Technical research

Software Development and management in Java EE, Node.js,

React js, C++, Objective-C, .Net, PHP, Python

### --- Chief Technology Officer

#### Aradiom

Sep 2007 - Dec 2011 (4 years 4 months)

Leading the technical team of Aradiom which is the provider of many Mobile Applications in the field of finance and Governmental organizations.

Using and Applying the whole PMI management processes for the whole projects of Aradiom.

Developing Software using the Agile methodologies.

## CEO and CTO

#### CREA TECH

May 2004 - Dec 2010 (6 years 8 months)

Play the Key role in starting Crea Technology which is the Turkcell Solution provider as well as the provider of many Mobile Applications which are accounted as the first to be done in Turkey and they are used by the biggest two Telsim VAS Providers. As well as managing the company as a CEO, play the role of CTO in leading the technical team in developing many Software's in different fields.

Using and Applying the whole PMI management processes for the whole projects of Crea.

Play the key role in innovation, designing and producing many electrical electronic and mechatronic products.

## Chief Technology Officer

AO Neu Media GmbH

May 2002 - Mar 2004 (1 year 11 months)

Leading the technical team in AO for researching and developing the new technologies in the telecommunication sector and come up with new projects of VAS (SMS, EMS, MMS) platforms, applications, Java applications, games (J2ME) and IVR applications.

### Co-founder and CTO

#### Aradiom

Nov 2001 - Apr 2002 (6 months)

Play a Key role in starting Aradiom which is the Turkcell Solution provider as well as the provider of many Mobile Applications in the Turkish and international market. Works as an CTO leading the software development team in developing many Software's in the telecommunications field.

### **Zed** Web Project Leader

Zed

Feb 2001 - Oct 2001 (9 months)

Responsible for managing and developing the ZED web site (marketing and product pages including web interface of all pull and push VAS services). Also responsible for managing and developing web reporting tools and content management system.

## Internet Project Leader

Argesoft

Nov 1999 - Jan 2001 (1 year 3 months)

Leads, architects and develops many Internet, Intranet, E-commerce projects.

### Software Developer and Architect

Aug 1998 - Nov 1999 (1 year 4 months)

Software architect and developer of the e-commerce, internet and intranet projects of Sentim (a distributor of the International company DELL).

### Software Engineer

ARGESOFT YAZILIM A.Ş.

Jul 1997 - Aug 1998 (1 year 2 months)

Part of the development team of the AgreLease software product (A project for the leasing companies).

### 3D Software Developer

Aug 1996 - Jun 1997 (11 months)

The analysis and implementation of the Digitalica Editing, 3D effects and Still Image and Video Processing Solutions.

### Lecturer

High Technical Institute

Oct 1995 - Jun 1996 (9 months)

A lecturer in the Computer Engineering Department of the High Technical Institute in Libya: Software Engineering, Data Structures, Project Life Cycle and Management.

### **Education**

### Al-Nahrain University

Master of Science (MSc.), Software Engineering 1992 - 1995

## Al-Nahrain University

Bachelor of Science (BS), Software Engineering 1988 - 1992

## Skills

CTO • IT Manager • Projects Management • Software Engineering • Software Development • Objective-C • Java Enterprise Edition • Android • Scrum • Software Project Management